

# Tomek Buszewski

Front-end architect / Senior developer

Nationality: Polish

Date and place of birth: 8.09.1989, Sanok, Poland

Address: Bluszczańska 76/197, 00-712 Warsaw

**Phone:** +48 784 85 11 46

E-mail: tomek.buszewski@gmail.com

Portfolio: www.buszewski.com

GitHub: www.github.com/tomekbuszewski

#### **About**

Senior front-end developer with over 10 years of commercial experience. Capable of managing projects from start (writing concepts, choosing technology, creating boilerplate and style guides) to finish (active development with strong understanding of agile methodology). Experienced both as a team member and leader.

#### **Skills and Traits**

- Clean and documented code fanatic;
- Able to create scalable project architecture from scratch;
- · Functional and object-oriented programming user;
- Experienced in optimization of front-end layer of web;
- Rest API and GraphQL user;
- Experienced in implementing new technologies in existing projects;
- Able to create PoC and develop them into working applications;
- Writes tests with good code coverage;
- Strict code reviewer;
- Proven team leader;
- Good team player;

# **Technology Stack**

Frameworks and Libraries • React, Redux, Router, Gatsby;

Angular 1.x, jQuery;

Axios, Fetch, Immutable, Apollo;

Bootstrap, Bulma, Tachyons, JSS;

Express;

Symfony 2/3, Django, Flask;

**Build Tools etc.** • Webpack, Gulp, Rollup, Docker (with Compose);

Preprocessors, Transpilers etc. • Babel, SCSS, Less, PostCSS;

Code Quality Assistance • ESLint, TSLint, Stylelint, Flow Type;

React Storybook;

Testing • Jest, Enzyme, Mocca, Karma, Protractor, Nightwatch;

Programming Languages • JavaScript (ES6/7 and lower), TypeScript, CSS, HTML, NodeJS, GraphQL, Python, PHP;

Graphic Tools • Photoshop, Illustrator, Sketch, Corel Draw;

Project Management • JIRA, Redmine, ZenHub, Mantis;

Operating Systems • macOS;

# **Work Experience**

#### Batmaid.com

Lead Front-End Developer / Team Leader

2019.02 — ongoing

- Developing new version of the client application from the ground up:
  - Responsible for the entire architecture and stack;
  - Using React with TypeScript, Redux and Styled Components as base;
  - Introducing Storybook for UI development and Jest for testing;
  - Introducing Cypress for E2E tests;
  - Developing mock API basing on Swagger definitions in Node (with Express) and Python (with Flask).
- Managing front-end team:
  - Active participation in recruitment, from consultation on advertisement to taking part in the interviews for both front-end and iOS developers and testers:
  - conducting evaluation and feedback meetings with team members;
  - team members' mentorship in terms of technical aspects.

#### 4Finance / vivus.pl

Area Lead / Senior Front-end Developer

2018.05 - 2018-11

- Managing and mentoring front-end teams in Poland and Lithuania (remotely):
  - Conducting 1 on 1 meetings;
  - Providing support in both technical and "soft" terms;
  - Managing team capacity in terms of development;
- · Member of core web team;
- Refactoring legacy code to newest standards;
- Creating new React components for various products in 4Finance portfolio.

## Zety.com / interviewme.pl Senior Front-end Developer

2017.08 - 2018.05

- Rewriting outdated creator application from scratch using React and Redux;
- Creating from scratch user interface for managing companies profiles (React, Redux, GraphQL integration);
- Reformatting existing project structure:
  - Introducing thorough code commenting system and strict file naming;
  - Refactoring old JavaScript modules from one-time classes to modules;
  - Splitting code base into chunks (using Webpack), separating vendors and common code from site modules.

# Gremi Media / Parkiet.com / RP.pl Team Leader / Senior Front-end Developer

2016.06 - 2017.08

- Managing team working on the new version of Parkiet.com:
  - Creating and managing tasks in agile manner;
  - Systematic code review;
  - Release versioning;
- Creating new front-end architecture for both Parkiet.com and RP.pl:
  - Introducing Webpack, ES6, React, Redux and various other libraries;
  - Code guidance for both RP and Parkiet.com teams;
- Writing React components and JavaScript modules for both Parkiet.com and RP.pl;
- Reviewing and refactoring code received from front-end subcontractor.

#### Ars Thanea / Syzygy

Front-end Developer

Slicing PSD to Twig templates;

Writing Angular.js directives and components;

2015.09 - 2016.04

Writing jQuery modules and snippets;

# Work Experience (cont.)

**Eurozet / Radio ZET** 

Writing jQuery modules and snippets;

Front-end Developer

· Refactoring some of the legacy code;

2014.09 - 2015.09

Implementing new functionalities and modules on Eurozet's websites;

Writing new front-end for zetgold.pl;

buszewski.com

Designing web and mobile interfaces;

Full-Stack Developer / Designer

Writing jQuery and VanillaJS code snippets and modules;

2008.09 - ongoing

• Integrating front-end with various content management (mainly WordPress);

 $\bullet \qquad \text{Writing back-end solutions in PHP (mostly without any framework,} \\$ 

later Codelgniter);

## **Education**

SHVS in Sanok

Polish philology - communications in media

2011 - 2014

SHVS in Sanok

Mechanics in engineering

2008 - 2009